[wind howling]
[Qifrey grunts]
[ALAIRA] What's the point
of having a stairway
if no one's going to use it?
It's been a long time
since you last came here
to the seabed.
Problem child of the Great Hall.
Those days are long past,
Alaira, charmed.
Are they, now?
As I understand it,
you've been stirring up
trouble again.
I know all about
your new apprentice.
[QIFREY] Already?
Word travels fast.
[ALAIRA] You think
she has the connection
you're looking for?
To the Brimmed Caps, that is?
It's been four years
since anyone's used
forbidden magic.
She's a vital lead.
That has nothing to do with it.
And she's not my apprentice yet,
she hasn't even been tested.
[ALAIRA] Well,
what are you waiting for?
[QIFREY] She's still new,
and now is not the time.
Ah, yes, of course.
The test is held
at the Dadah Range,
and this time of year.
The elevation is going to be
at its highest point.
I wouldn't dream of testing
someone in such conditions.
They could be killed.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[birds chirping]
[COCO] Um, Agott?
Are you sure about this?
With Master Qifrey gone...
THE DADAH RANGE TEST
It's something you're going
to have to do alone,
whether he's here or not.
[COCO] But aren't we
rushing things a bit?
I just got here!
I passed this test
when I was ten years old.
It's required of everyone
who wishes
to become an apprentice,
including yourself.
I see.
[AGOTT] The first test is called
"Consent of the Crown."
You're only allowed the use
of three contraptions
and your components.
Your objective is to reach
the summit of the Dadah Range
purely on your own power,
and when you do,
to pick the Diadem Herb
that grows there.
The Guidance Orb,
to point the way
to your destination,
and the Vapor Bubble,
for drinking water.
That's probably
all you can handle
for the moment.
Now, begone.
- One last thing.
- Mm?
Could I possibly have
some shoes like yours?
Some shoes?
[COCO] They'd count as
my third contraption, right?
You and Master Qifrey
both have them.
The soles light up
when you fly.
So, uh... I was wondering
if maybe, you might, uh...
be willing to lend me a pair?
Eh...
Of course not! That was
too much to ask! Sorry!
Forget I said anything!
[Agott inhales, exhales deeply]
[Coco gasps]
You may borrow mine.
And with that settled...
[COCO] Thank you.
[AGOTT]
...it's time you were off!
[Coco grunts]
Oh, I almost forgot.
When it comes to this test,
you won't be getting
any second chances.
If you should fail,
you'll be disqualified
from ever becoming
Master Qifrey's apprentice,
and required
to leave the atelier.
[Coco gasps]
- [wings flapping]
- [Coco whimpers]
All of a sudden I'm terrified.
But I can't turn back.
I have to do all I can!
So this is a Guidance Orb.
But how do I use it?
[clinking]
[Coco exclaims]
Is it telling me
I should go this way?
Right!
A little mountain-climbing?
Simple!
[yelps]
[grunts]
♪
I can do it!
After all, Agott did it
when she was ten!
[yelps]
If she could do it that young,
then surely I...
[Coco screams]
Surely, I...
[yelps]
[gasps]
No.
It can't be.
This is it?
This is the Dadah Range?
[footsteps]
The Guidance Orb
is pointing directly at it.
That must be it, then.
[sighs]
Someone could have told me
it would be floating in the air.
[bird screeching]
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] Yes!
I knew it was smart
to ask her for these!
Fly!
Uh?
- [wind blows]
- [Coco grunts]
[Coco sighs]
Half the Casting Seal
on one foot,
and half on the other.
If I put them together,
and align them perfectly.
[Coco gasps]
[exclaims]
[laughs]
Look at me!
I'm floating off the ground!
[whimpers]
[screams]
Master Qifrey
had it exactly right.
I'm an awkward,
clumsy little foal.
- [bird screeching]
- [gasps]
And yet...
[bird screeching]
I can fly.
♪
If I fly, I'll reach
the summit in no time!
Now...
Here I go!
[thuds]
[QIFREY] Don't you worry.
You'll be running wild
in no time at all.
[Coco grunts]
[COCO] Running wild.
Running wild.
Could you please
process this application?
- Right. Thotrey, number twelve.
- Of course.
You know, you wouldn't
have to travel
for this sort of thing
if you lived in the Great Hall.
Your apprentices
would be welcome here, too.
The Great Hall is
the witches' stronghold.
Everything a witch could need
can be found here.
And so, when I need something,
I come.
All right, here you are!
[QIFREY] Thank you.
Your hate for the Great Hall
runs deep, eh?
Well, keep an eye
on those apprentices of yours.
With children that age,
you never know
what they might get up to
when left to their own devices.
[whimpering]
[COCO] That's good!
I think I'm getting better
at maintaining my balance!
Maybe I should try going
a little higher.
[grunts, screams]
♪
[grunts, exhales]
[Coco sighs]
[COCO] Huh?
[squeaks]
[Coco gasps]
[screams]
[panting]
[COCO] A brushbuddy!
I've never seen one before!
[Coco sighs]
[groans]
Agott's shoes are covered
with mud now. Great.
[brushbuddy chirps]
[Coco gasps softly]
[gasps] No, no, what happened?
The seal is coming off!
It's all my fault,
I wiped it off!
Oh, no, oh, no,
oh, no! What now?
I know! I'll just draw it
back on!
[Coco squeals nervously]
Would you look at that,
the Conjuring Ink spilled
in my bag somehow.
[brushbuddy sniffs]
[squeaks]
What am I supposed to do?
Is it all over?
So, uh... Agott, have you
seen Coco around?
It's going to be dinner time
pretty soon.
Coco's not here right now.
She left for the Dadah Range
a while ago to take her test.
What, all by herself?
But she just got to the atelier
a short time ago!
Why didn't you stop her?
Really, Agott!
[AGOTT] Most would have taken
the test before coming here.
You're right, but...
[AGOTT] If she can't pass
a test as simple as that,
then she has no business
being an apprentice.
Understand.
I refuse to tolerate those
who can't reach my level.
Their presence
has no value to me.
Especially if they're also
Outsiders.
There's no need to worry.
She'll be back soon enough,
after she's failed.
During this season,
the Dadah Range reaches
its greatest altitude.
She'll never reach such heights
with only my Sylph Shoes
to carry her.
She's ignorant of the rules
and unaware of the danger
she's put herself in.
I don't want
to share our world
with someone like that.
[Tetia whines]
So are you not eating?
[groans] I will, but...
I guess I'm just feeling
a little bit down right now.
[Richeh gasps softly]
[TETIA] Huh?
[RICHEH] Seconds.
Am I really the only one
who's the least bit worried
around here?
What can we do, except wait
for Master Qifrey to return?
[Tetia groans]
[Coco grunting]
[Coco sighs] It's no use.
I tried drawing it back on
with what's left of the ink,
but I'm still not getting off
the ground at all.
[sighs]
The ink's smearing
because the shoes are wet.
What if I drew on the soles
of my feet?
[Coco gasps]
No, I can't!
Magic directly involving
the human body is forbidden.
I don't have the first clue
of what kind of spell would help
at a time like this.
[brushbuddy squeaks]
I guess Agott was right,
wasn't she?
[Tetia exclaims]
[COCO] Anyone can learn
how to draw spells,
but that doesn't mean
they'll be good at using magic.
Maybe I need to accept
that only someone special
can become a witch.
[BOTH] Huh?
[Coco gasps]
♪
[COCO] All of them
have been drawing spells
since they were children.
It's not something
I could ever...
[Coco gasps]
[COCO'S MOTHER] Hm.
[Coco gasps] Mm.
There... Nice and straight.
- [Coco's mother gasps]
- [Coco screams]
- [COCO'S MOTHER] Coco.
- Boo! [laughs]
[COCO] Uh?
[QIFREY] My!
I had no idea
this village possessed
such a skilled artisan.
This is real magic.
[Coco gasps]
[brushbuddy squeals]
That's it.
♪
[COCO] I have my own magic!
[wind blowing]
[Coco panting]
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[COCO] If I let a little water
soak in and dilute it...
My cape's a little stiff
from all the dried mud.
I think I can draw on it.
[brushbuddy squeaks]
♪
[QIFREY] It's natural
to be unsteady
when you're getting
used to something new.
[COCO] In that case,
how about something
I'm already used to?
My fingers begin to dance
of their own accord.
Freely.
[brushbuddy squeaks softly]
[wind blowing]
[COCO] There!
Good morning, Brushbuddy!
You've made yourself at home,
haven't you?
It's a pretty ugly Casting Seal,
I know.
Ideally, the sigil
should be centered,
and the signs
are supposed to be uniform.
[brushbuddy squeaks softly]
[COCO] I just learned
if they aren't balanced,
it can send too much energy
in one direction.
So I wondered
what would happen
if I made one long on purpose!
I can't be sure
if it'll work, though.
- [brushbuddy squeals]
- [Coco yelps]
[laughs]
You want to come with me?
[brushbuddy squeaks]
All right, but I need you
to hold on tight for me.
And now to close the ring.
[wind gushing]
- [Coco gasps]
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
[COCO] What? What's happening?
I don't understand!
Did I get
the sign's direction wrong?
- [Coco screaming]
- [brushbuddy squeaking]
[wood creaking]
[Coco continues screaming]
[Coco grunting]
I did it, brushbuddy!
I'm flying, with my own magic!
My dream has finally
come to life.
A cloak of flight!
♪
In the end,
I learned to use magic
using what I learned
from helping Mom.
Unbelievable.
But the Diadem Herb's up higher!
♪
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] There it is!
[Coco screams, grunts]
♪
[Coco grunting]
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[screaming]
[Coco grunting]
♪
[Coco exclaims, laughs]
[Coco pants]
[COCO] Mom...
[whimpers]
[grunts]
[COCO] Hold on, Mom!
Wait for me!
I don't know how yet,
but I will make things right!
[QIFREY] What?
You're saying Coco went
to the Dadah Range alone
- to be tested?
- [TETIA] Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
It's too dangerous!
I need to go
and save her at once!
But if you interfere,
she'll fail the test!
[QIFREY]
It was too soon for her
to attempt it
in the first place.
She hasn't been living
around magic
her whole life like we have.
And if anything were
to happen to Coco,
we'd lose so much
more than just her.
There.
[COCO] Uh?
- [brushbuddy squeals]
- Hello.
[QIFREY AND TETIA] Coco!
[cries] Thank goodness!
I'm so glad you're all right!
I can't tell you how sick
with worry I was about you!
[brushbuddy squeaks]
Agott, look!
The "Consent of the Crown."
I did it.
[Agott grunts softly]
This is the proof
I needed to get, right?
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
- [COCO] Huh?
Uh...
Coco, in the absence of
proper training and preparation,
meddling with magic
can prove extremely dangerous.
I thought you'd learned that.
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
- [Coco sighs]
That test could very easily
have cost you your life.
You must never do
anything like that again.
I understand, and I'm sorry.
Besides, you needn't have
endangered yourself
to prove anything.
Because you're already
my new apprentice.
[Tetia squeals, laughs]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
- [Coco exclaims]
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
[gasps] This is...
[brushbuddy squeals]
[QIFREY] I give you
the mark of a witch.
A symbol of our pride,
and of our solemn vow
never to use magic for evil.
[QIFREY] As long as
it rests upon your head,
you mustn't forget its weight.
The pointed cap
shall watch over you,
and your magic.
See that you take
good care of it.
Right!
Now, shall we
all return upstairs?
We shall!
[Coco's stomach grumbles]
[Tetia chuckles]
I think someone needs
a bite to eat!
And more importantly, a bath.
♪
[WITCH] The seed has sprouted.
EPISODE 4:
MEETINGS IN KALHN